ANIL ENES CALIS

SRE & DevOps Engineer

anilenescalis.github.io

As an SRE and DevOps engineer with +2 year experience, I have background in managing and continually optimizing container technologies, cloud platforms and on-premise systems. I have been effective in integrating new technologies and open-source software by prioritizing the security of the systems. In addition, I am a strong person in close cooperation with other engineers, active listening, systematic communication and leadership skills.

EXPERIENCES

LC Waikiki Sep. 2022 - Current

SRE & DevOps Engineer

Istanbul, Turkey

- Designing, operating and troubleshooting large-scale, high-availability distributed systems
- Developing a tool to automate the creation of a Kubernetes cluster using IaC following SOLID principles
- Automating the deployment and updates of applications on Bootstrapping Kubernetes with ArgoCD bootstrap in accordance with CI/CD processes and DevOps culture
- Ensuring cost optimization improvement with performance tuning of servers and cloud technologies on on-premises and cloud platforms
- Providing logging and monitoring structures and troubleshooting their infrastructure using open-source tools

LC Waikiki Aug. 2021 - Sep. 2022

Junior SRE & DevOps Engineer

Istanbul, Turkey

- Managing of Cloud Platforms and Container Orchestration Platforms
- Improving Automation for Systems
- Installing Open-Source Application and Monitoring Tools
- Linux and Windows Server Configuration
- Experiencing in troubleshooting and Monitoring of Applications using Golden Signals
- Basic knowledge of firewall, load balancer and network

EDUCATION

Eskisehir Osmangazi University

Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Electronics Engineer

Sep. 2014 - Oct. 2020 Eskisehir, Turkey

SKILLS

- +2 years of experience managing cloud-based infrastructure cloud providers such Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud
- Knowledge of high availability and system reliability, and how infrastructure is designed to run smoothly
- Knowledge of version control systems (Git) and Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) tools (Azure Devops, Argo CD)
- Knowledge of skills in using monitoring and bug tracking tools to monitor performance and detect problems (Grafana, Kibana, OpenSearch, ElasticSearch, Prometheus, Zabbix)
- Experienced in programming and automation skills to automate infrastructure and reduce repetitive tasks. (Shell Scripting, Powershell Scripting Python, Terraform, Packer, Ansible)
- +1 year of experience in container orchestration platforms and tools (Google Kubernetes Engine, Microsoft Azure Kubernetes Service, Kubernetes, Rancher, Docker Swarm)
- +1 year of experience in middleware tools such as Distributed Tracing Tools, Caching Tools, Message Brokers (Redis, RabbitMQ, Kafka, Nginx, Jaeger, İstio)
- Good knowledge about Windows Operation System and Linux Operating System

CERTIFICATES

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals (Validation Number: I629-5963)